我们将回过头来考虑这个矩阵导数的旋转部分。
We're going to go back to considering the rotational part of this matrix derivative.
我们将重新排列其表达式并隔离偏斜对称矩阵。这意味着
We're going to rearrange its expression and isolate the skew-symmetric matrix. That means
我们必须将旋转矩阵移到等式的另一边。我们要
we have to take the rotation matrix over to the other side of the equation. We need to
计算它的逆，但我们知道旋转度量，逆与其转置相同。
compute its inverse but we know for a rotation metrics that the inverse is the same as its transpose.
所以现在我们根据旋转矩阵的导数得到了斜对称矩阵
So now we have the skew-symmetric matrix in terms of the derivative of the rotation matrix
关于Q1，这是我们在这里以红色突出显示的近似值。该
with respect to Q1 and that's the approximation that we've got highlighted here in red. The
旋转矩阵转置和机器人关节角度的变化率。我们可以
rotation matrix transpose and the rate of change of the robot's joint angle. We can
用数值计算这个，我们最终得到这个矩阵，它应该是一个斜对称矩阵。
compute this numerically and we end up with this matrix which should be a skew-symmetric matrix.
让我们更详细地看一下它。我们知道有一个偏斜对称矩阵
Let's have a look at it in a bit more detail. We know that a skew-symmetric matrix has got
这样的形式，让我们检查这是否是一个斜对称矩阵和
a form something like this so let's check whether this is a skew-symmetric matrix and
如果是的话，角速度的值是多少？
if it is, what are the values of the angular velocity?
一开始，如果我们看一下对角线，我们可以看到它们是零或非常，
At the start if we look at the diagonals we can see that they are either zero or very,
非常接近零，并记住这是一个近似值，所以我会说手
very close to zero and remember that this is an approximation so I'm going to say hand
在心脏上，这些是对角线上的零。它看起来像一个斜对称矩阵
on heart that these are zeroes on the diagonal. It's looking like a skew-symmetric matrix
对我来说。让我们看一下与OmegaX相对应的元素。在这种情况下，它们都是零
to me. Let's look at the elements that correspond to Omega X. In this case they're both zero
所以我们可以写出OmegaX大约等于Q1dot的零次。我们来看看吧
so we can write that Omega X is approximately equal to zero times Q1dot. Let's look at the
OmegaY元素和它们都相同，所以我很高兴地说Omega
Omega Y elements and they are both identically equal to zero so I'm happy to say that Omega
Y大约等于Q1dot的零次。
Y is approximately equal to zero times Q1dot.
现在让我们来看看OmegaZ，这与OmegaZ大致相当
Let's look now at Omega Z and this is pretty consistent with Omega Z being approximately
等于Q1dot的1倍。所以我们所做的就是匹配精确偏斜对称的元素
equal to 1 times Q1dot. So what we've done is match the elements in an exact skew-symmetric
矩阵和近似的斜对称矩阵并写出一些关系
matrix and are approximate skew-symmetric matrix and written some relationships between
机器人末端执行器的角速度和第一个的变化率的组成部分
the components of the robot end-effector angular velocity and the rate of change of the first
Q1dot的关节角度。
joint angle that's Q1dot.
所以我现在可以用这样的矩阵形式来编写它，这里再次表达了这个表达式
So I can write it now in matrix form like this, and here's that expression again and
带回我们之前为机器人的过渡速度计算的表达式
to bring back the expression we computed earlier for the transitional velocity of the robot's
最终的效应。我可以通过叠加两个向量并将其结合起来来组合这两个
end-effector. And I can combine these two by stacking up the two vectors and bringing
排除Q1dot的常用术语。
out the common term Q1dot.
而我现在在机器人的末端执行器的空间速度之间存在这种关系
And I now have this relationship between the spatial velocity of the robot's end-effector
和机器人的第一个关节角度的速度。所以这就是我们的表达方式
and the velocity of the robot's first joint angle. So here's the expression that we just
计算出来，我们可以为关节2和关节3一直做到同样的事情，一直到关节6。
computed and we can do the same thing for joint 2 and joint 3 all the way up to joint 6.
您会注意到矩阵顶部和向量的向量中的数字是
You'll notice that the numbers in the vectors at the top and the columns of the matrix are
略有不同，那是因为顶部的向量是近似值
slightly different and that's because the vectors at the top are an approximation to
真正的导数，而带矩阵的列是真正的导数。这里的
the true derivative while the columns with the matrix are the true derivative. Here's
再次矩阵，它将空间速度与机器人的关节速度联系起来
the matrix again and it relates the spatial velocity to the robot's joint velocity by
中间的这个矩阵是雅可比矩阵的另一个实例。这是一个6x6
this matrix in the middle which is another instance of a Jacobian matrix. It's a 6 x 6
矩阵和它被称为操纵器雅可比矩阵。我们可以写这个表达式
matrix and it’s referred to as the manipulator Jacobian matrix. We can write this expression
更加简洁。
much more succinctly.
我们使用希腊字母'nu'来表示空间速度和
We use the Greek letter ‘nu’ as we have done previously to represent spatial velocity and
我们通过Qdot表示联合速度。我用大写字母J代表操纵者
we represent joint velocity by Qdot. I've used capital J to represent the manipulator
Jacobian和我已经表明它是Q的函数。雅可比矩阵的元素
Jacobian and I've indicated that it is a function of Q. The elements of the Jacobian matrix
取决于关节角度。
depend on the joint angles.
现在我们要为Puma560机器人计算精确的雅可比行列式，我已经装好了
Now we're going to compute the exact Jacobian for the Puma 560 robot and I've already loaded
机器人进入我工作区的模型。我要把雅可比人放到工作区
a model of the robot into my workspace. I'm going to put the Jacobian into the workspace
对于变量J和我的机器人对象称为P560和我要调用的方法
for variable J and my robot object is called P560 and the method that I'm going to invoke
被称为雅可比行列式，我传入的唯一论证是关节角度的集合。
is called Jacobian and the only argument that I've passed in is the set of joint angles.
这里是雅可比矩阵，它是针对关节角集合计算的
And here is the Jacobian matrix and that's being computed for the set of joint angles
QN，这就是它在弧度上的样子，这是一套机器人配置
QN and this is what it looks like in radians and this is a robot configuration a set of
机器人关节角度，将机器人的末端执行器置于其有用工作空间的中间位置。
robot joint angles that puts the robot’s end-effector somewhere in the middle of its useful workspace.
考虑雅可比矩阵的一种有用方法是根据各列的内容
A useful way to think about the Jacobian matrix is in terms of what the individual columns
意思。雅可比矩阵的第一列乘以第一列的变化率
mean. The first column of the Jacobian matrix multiplied by the rate of change of the first
关节给了我对末端效应器空间速度的贡献。
joint gives me a contribution to the end-effector’s spatial velocity.
此列给出了由Q2引起的末端效应器速度的一个组成部分。这是组件
And this column gives me a component of end-effector velocity due to Q2. This is the component
由于Q3，Q4，Q5和Q6。然后我们根据每个关节添加组件以获得总和
due to Q3, Q4, Q5 and Q6. And we add the components due to each of these joints to get the sum
总末端执行器空间速度。
total end-effector spatial velocity.